LANGUAGE

CURRENCY

€ EUR

$ USD

£ GBP

SAVE

SUPPORT

+352 263 725 200

[Our website uses cookies.](https://www.eurodns.com/use-of-cookies) Some of the cookies used are essential for parts of the site to operate.

Accept

ENGLISHFRANÇAISDEUTSCHESPAÑOL

Privacy Policy
==============

This Privacy Policy explains what kind of personal data we collect from you when you use our services and how we use that data. When we say “EuroDNS", “we" and “us", we are referring to EuroDNS S.A. and all of our affiliates.  

**Scope**

This policy applies to every EuroDNS customer and/or prospect (individuals, though not companies or organisations) without distinction of your nationality or place of residence.  

The type of personal data we process and how it is processed depends on the services provided.

I. Personal data collection and processing
------------------------------------------

### 1\. EuroDNS website visitors and prospects

#### A. Cookies

We collect information and potential personal data about our website visitors by the use of cookies. For more information, please see our cookie policy: [https://www.eurodns.com/use-of-cookies](http://www.eurodns.com/use-of-cookies)

#### B. Interaction

We may collect other data that you submit via our social media accounts as well as other means of communication. For example, we may collect personal data when you provide feedback or when you participate in interactive features such as surveys, contests, or promotions.

#### C. Newsletter subscribers

In case you subscribe to our newsletter, certain personal data may be transferred to our partner, The Rocket Science Group, LLC 675 Ponce de Leon Ave NE, Suite 5000, Atlanta, GA 30308, USA, who is operating MailChimp, the service we use to manage the sending of our newsletter. While they don’t have access to your data, it is nonetheless hosted on their platform.

**Type of data**  
Email address, first and last name, IP addresses.  
  
**Basis and Purpose**  
This processing is based on your consent. We collect and process this data to customise and improve our services.~  
  
~**Retention**  
We keep all personal data we collect outside the scope of the provision of our services for a period of one (1) year or until you request its deletion.  

### 2\. EuroDNS customers

As a EuroDNS customer you may provide us with personal data for several purposes.  

#### A. Account information

In order to create and manage your account on our platform, you need to provide us with sufficient information to allow us to identify you.

**Type of data**  
Email address, first and last name, postal address, language preference, your login, your IP address.  
  
**Basis and Purpose**  
We only collect and process this data for the provision of our service.  
  
**Retention**  
We keep your personal data for as long as you hold an account with EuroDNS. Should you want to close your account, please contact support@eurodns.com and we will anonymise all personal data attached to your account. However, please be aware that in certain cases regulatory or legal obligations may prevent EuroDNS from completely deleting your personal data. For example, we are required to keep every invoice we issue for ten (10) years.

#### B. Payment Information

We collect certain payment and billing information when you order paid services. For example, we ask you to designate a billing contact, including name and contact information. You might also provide payment information, such as payment card details or PayPal identifiers.

**Type of data**  
Partial credit card information including first and last name, and PayPal account identifier.~  
  
~**Basis and Purpose**  
We only collect and process this data for the provision of our service.  
  
**Retention**  
We keep your personal data for as long as you hold an account with EuroDNS. Should you want to close your account, please contact [support@eurodns.com](mailto:support@eurodns.com) and we will anonymise all personal data attached to your account. However, please be aware that in certain cases regulatory or legal obligations may prevent EuroDNS from completely deleting your personal data. For example, we are required to keep every invoice we issue for ten (10) years.  

#### C. Information you provide through our support channels

Our service includes access to our customer support department. When you open a support ticket, speak to one of our representatives directly, or otherwise engage with our support team, you will be asked to provide contact information, a summary of your request for support, and other relevant information. When you contact our customer support department, your personal data may be transferred to   SALESFORCE.COM EMEA LIMITED  110 Bishopsgate  village 9, floor 26 Salesforce Tower London EC2N 4AY  United-Kingdom,  the entity providing the help desk software Desk.com which we use to assist you.  

While they don’t have access to your data, it is nonetheless hosted on their platform.

**Type of data**  
Any data provided by you when submitting a request for support.  
  
**Basis and Purpose**  
We only collect and process this data for the provision of our service.**Retention**  
We keep your personal data for as long as you hold an account with EuroDNS. Should you want to close your account, please contact [support@eurodns.com](mailto:support@eurodns.com) and we will anonymise all personal data attached to your account. However, please be aware that in certain cases regulatory or legal obligations may prevent EuroDNS from completely deleting your personal data.  

#### D. Domain Name service

For this service, you will be required to provide additional personal data by creating contact profiles which will be transferred to each registry with whom you want to register a domain name. Additionally, in case you have selected a so-called generic extension, a copy of your contact profiles will also be stored with DENIC Services GmbH & Co. KG Heinrich-Hertz-Str. 6, 64295 Darmstadt, Germany, which is the ICANN-authorised escrow service provider that we use.  

**Type of data**  
First and last name, postal address, email address, phone number.  
  
**Basis and Purpose**  
Collection and processing of this data is necessary to comply with our legal obligations as data processor for registries. Transfer of relevant data is a mandatory requirement by the registries who have a monopoly on the extensions they manage.  
  
**Retention**  
Each registry has its own retention period but in general this does not exceed two years after the deletion of the Domain Name. For further information, please refer to the applicable registry policy: [https://www.eurodns.com/regist...](https://www.eurodns.com/registries-policies)**Transfer Abroad**  
Depending on the registry you would like to register a domain name with, your personal data may be transferred outside the EEA.  

**No guarantee**  
**When registering a domain name with a registry established outside the EEA (Europe), you expressly understand and agree that this registry is not bound by the same privacy laws as EuroDNS and that, in some cases, no protection of your personal data is offered.  
To benefit from an adequate level of protection of your personal data, you should register your domain name under a European extension or, alternatively, an extension managed by a registry established within the EEA.**

In case of doubt, don’t hesitate to contact our legal department at [legal@eurodns.com](mailto:legal@eurodns.com).  

#### E. Open-Xchange

For the provision of this service, we will share some of your personal data with our partner Open-Xchange AG Rollnerstraße 14  
D-90408 Nuernberg, Germany.

**Type of data**  
Email address created as part of the Open-Xchange service.  
  
**Basis and Purpose**  
We only collect and process this data for the provision of our service.**Retention**  
Your personal data is immediately deleted upon termination or expiration of the service.  

#### F. Office 365

For the provision of this service, we will share some of your personal data with our partner Microsoft Ireland Operations Limited One Microsoft Place, South County Business Park, Leopardstown, Dublin 18, Ireland

**Type of data**  
Email address created as part of the Open-Xchange service.

**Basis and Purpose**  
We only collect and process this data for the provision of our service.

**Retention**  
Your personal data is immediately deleted upon termination or expiration of the service.

#### F. SSL Certificate

For the provision of this service, we will share some of your personal data with the certification authority of your choice:

GMO GlobalSign

Ltd Springfield House,

Sandling Road, Maidstone

Kent, ME14 2LP

Royaume-Uni

or

Sectigo Limited

Unit 7 & 9 Listerhills, Science Park, Campus Road, Bradford, BD7 1HR Royaume-Uni

**Type of data**  
First and last name, email address, postal address, phone number.  
  
**Basis and Purpose**  
We only collect and process this data for the provision of our service.  
  
**Retention**  
Your personal data is immediately deleted upon termination or expiration of the service.  

#### G. TradeMark Clearing House service

For the provision of this service, we will share some of your personal data with CHIP S.A. 24, rue Léon Laval L-3372 Leudelange, Luxembourg, the TMCH service provider.

**Type of data**  
All data attached to your Trademark registration.  
  
**Basis and Purpose**  
We only collect and process this data for the provision of our service.

**Retention**  
Your personal data is immediately deleted upon termination or expiration of the service.  

#### H. Webhosting

This service does not require the provision of additional personal data.

#### I. DNS Services

This service does not require the provision of additional personal data.

II. Your rights in relation to your personal data
-------------------------------------------------

Unless your request is deemed excessive or unfounded, you may exercise the following rights in relation to your personal data:  

**1\. Right of access**  

You have the right to request a copy of the personal data that we hold about you. You may do so via your EuroDNS account [https://my.eurodns.com/account/preferences#](http://my.eurodns.com/account/preferences#) or, alternatively, request it at [support@eurodns.com](mailto:support@eurodns.com).

**2\. Right of rectification**

You have a right to correct data that we hold about you that is inaccurate or incomplete. You may do so via your EuroDNS account [https://my.eurodns.com/account/preferences#](http://my.eurodns.com/account/preferences#) or, alternatively, request it at [support@eurodns.com](mailto:support@eurodns.com).

**3\. Right to be forgotten**

In certain circumstances, you can ask for the data we hold about you to be erased from our records. Please contact [support@eurodns.com](mailto:support@eurodns.com) and we will anonymise all personal data attached to your account. However, please be aware that in certain cases regulatory or legal obligations may prevent EuroDNS from completely deleting your personal data.

**4\. Right of portability**

You have the right to have the data we hold about you transferred to another organisation. You may export your data via your EuroDNS account [https://my.eurodns.com/account/preferences#](http://my.eurodns.com/account/preferences#) or, alternatively, request it at [support@eurodns.com](mailto:support@eurodns.com).

**5\. Right to object**

You have the right to object to certain types of processing of your personal data such as direct marketing. To do so please contact our legal department at [legal@eurodns.com](mailto:legal@eurodns.com).

Lastly, you have the right to file a complaint with the Luxembourgish Data Protection Authority, when you are of the opinion that our processing of your personal data is not in compliance with applicable legislation. Their complaint form is accessible at: [https://cnpd.public.lu/fr/formulaires.html](https://cnpd.public.lu/fr/droits/faire-valoir/formulaire-plainte.html)  

III. Security Measures
----------------------

Your personal data is stored both electronically and manually in our data centres in Luxembourg and can be accessed from our offices via dedicated network connections or from anywhere through a secured VPN connection.  

We use a combination of technical, administrative, and physical controls to maintain the security of your data.  

Most importantly we are making use of specific technologies to encrypt all our services.

IV. Data Protection Officer Details
-----------------------------------

EuroDNS  
Luc Seufer  
24, rue Léon laval  
L-3372 Leudelange  
Luxembourg  

V. Changes to this Privacy Policy
---------------------------------

We may change this privacy policy from time to time. We will post any modifications on this page and, if they are significant, we will provide a more prominent notice, posted directly in your EuroDNS account or via email. We will also keep prior versions of this privacy policy in an archive for your review. We encourage you to review our privacy policy whenever you use our services to stay informed about our information practices and what you can do to help protect your security.  
  
If you disagree with any changes to this privacy policy, you will need to stop using our services and deactivate your EuroDNS account, as outlined above.  

#### Latest blog articles

* 06.06.2024[Branding and Domain Names: Impact of Domain Name on Brand Identity and Customer Perception](https://www.eurodns.com/blog/domain-names-brand-identity)
* 05.06.2024[The Ultimate Guide to Choosing the Perfect Domain ...](https://www.eurodns.com/blog/how-choose-perfect-domain-for-your-website)
* 30.05.2024[SEO and Domain Names: Increase your Search Ranking with SEO-friendly Domain Name](https://www.eurodns.com/blog/boost-seo-with-perfect-domain-name)
* 23.05.2024[What Exactly is Domain Authority and How Can it Boost your SEO?](https://www.eurodns.com/blog/what-is-domain-authority)

#### Domain Name Discounts

#### Receive our newsletter

* #### [Domain Names](https://www.eurodns.com/domain-name-search)

* #### [WordPress](https://www.eurodns.com/managed-wordpress-hosting)

* #### Web Hosting
    
* Plesk Web Hosting
* Web Hosting Comparison

* #### [Microsoft 365](https://www.eurodns.com/office-microsoft-365)

* #### [SSL Certificates](https://www.eurodns.com/ssl-certificate)
    
* Multi-domain SSL (SAN)

* #### [Email](https://www.eurodns.com/email-cloud-suite)

* #### [DNS Services](https://www.eurodns.com/dns-services)

* #### [Business](https://www.eurodns.com/business)

* #### Affiliates

* #### [Information](https://www.eurodns.com/information)

* #### [The Company](https://www.eurodns.com/about)

* #### Channels

* #### Help & Support

© 2002 - 2024 EuroDNS S.A. All rights reserved. \*Except where stated, all prices exclude VAT
